





Jump to Section | Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Projects |

#### Summary

Last Active: 22-Jan-21

15+ years of IT industry experience encompassing wide range of technical skill set. Working as Sr. Technical Architect with extensive experience in implementing new systems. Functional expertise in designing and developing frameworks using Java technologies. Excellent problem solving and trouble shooting skills.

Sun Certified(SR3303319) Java Programmer for Java 2 Platform 1.5

Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

# **Work Experience**

Stabilix Software Solutions Pvt. Ltd. as Senior Technical Architect -Java May 2011 to Till Date

Solution Expert, Technical Review of products, Design and Development, Technical mentoring of team members

■ IBS Software Services as Senior Software Engineer

Sep 2010 to May 2011

Full stack developer

Dimensions Financials Software Services Pvt. Ltd. as Senior Software Engineer Dec 2005 to Sep 2010

. ... . -

Full stack developer

^ Back to Top

#### Education

UG: B.Sc (Electronics) from Kerala University in 2000

 $\hbox{PG: } \textbf{PGDiploma (Computer Application)} \ \text{from IHRD, THRUVANANTHAPURAM in 2002}$ 

^ Back to Top

# IT Skills

# **Important**

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
spring boot	2.2	2020	4 Year(s)
SPRING M/C	5	2020	9 Year(s)
STRUTS2	2.3	2020	8 Year(s)
Hibernate	5.2	2020	12 Year(s)
RESTAPI		2020	4 Year(s)
JAVA			
JavaScript			
HtML, SQL			
JQUERY			
Hibernate, MyBatis			
Oracle, postgreSQL			
MySQL			
Apache Tomcat, JBOSS			
Maven, Apache Ant			
Apache ActiveMQ			
SVN, GIT, CVS			
Jenkins			
DOCKER			

^ Back to Top

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Malayalam				

^ Back to Top

# **Projects**

Project Title: Demarcation Tool - Admin Portal

Client: Genkey

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Aug 2020 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Roles & Responsibilities

Technical Architect:- technically managed and mentored team members

Design and implementation of Framework Complete development, testing and bug fixing,

Technologies Used

Spring Boot, Thymeleaf, Jquery, Hibernate, Oracle/Postgres

This product was designed and developed for the client Genkey. This product has deployed for two clients of Genkey in two different environments (One in Postgres and the other in Oracle). Only members of admin users groups can login to this portal and define their own demarcation details (State, Prefecture, Sub-prefecture, Village, County etc.) The defined demarcation will be approved by members of another higher authority admin groups. We can create new demarcation, move voters to the new demarcation, split voters. The approved demarcation will be transferred to the public voters portal's database through RestAPI (while maintenance).

Project Title: Health Companion Client: Health Companion Nature of Employment: Full Time Role: Solution Architect

Duration: Jan 2014 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Team Size: 12

Skill Used: Struts2, Spring, Hibernate, Apache ActiveMQ, Oracle, Spring RestAPI, Cryptography(AES)

Role Description: Solution Specialist Design and integration of new modules

Implementing Jenkins CI

**HSMIntegration** 

Project Details: Health Companion is a portal for patient engagement. All patient sensitive data are encrypted using the key which is stored in HSM. Health Companion was designed and implemented as SOA with dynamic code generation and integrated it with Health Companion in Continuous Integration (Jenkins). SOA implementation had done using Spring and REST API. In development environment, Health Companion will work as a single non-distributed project. In production and QA environments, it will works as an SOA architecture with 5 different services which can be deployed in 5 different servers.

Project Title: Direct Secure Messaging

Client: Multiple Clients

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Role: Other

Duration: Jan 2013 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 6

Skill Used: Spring M/C, Hibernate, James Mail Server, DNS Server, Apache ActiveMQ, Oracle, Spring RestAPI, Cryptography(RSA, AES)
Role Description: Technical Architect: - technically managed and mentored team members

Design and implementation of Framework

Complete development, testing, bug fixing, application deployment Implementing Jenkins Cl

Certification process

Project Details: Direct messaging is a national encryption standard for securely exchanging patient health information via secure web e-mail. Regular e-mail or fax involves the inherent risks of information being compromised or accessed by unauthorized users. Direct Messaging uses strong encryption methods for securely transmitting message over SMTP protocol

^ Back to Top

### **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.